const e="apes_ch4",s="Chapter 4",i=[{number:1,question:"Biodiversity refers to the variety of",choices:["energy flow and nutrient cycling that supports life in ecosystems.","all of the choices","ecosystems in which species live.","earth's species."],correct:1},{number:2,question:"Charles Darwin and Alfred Wallace both first proposed",choices:["that ecosystems evolve.","a mechanism for evolution.","all of the choices","that organisms evolve."],correct:1},{number:3,question:"Evolution",choices:["is supported by fossil evidence.","is a change in species over time.","all of the choices","results in genetically diverse species."],correct:2},{number:4,question:"A random change in an organism's DNA is called",choices:["evolution.","mutation.","natural selection.","adaptation."],correct:1},{number:5,question:"Populations, not individuals, evolve.",choices:["True","False"],correct:0},{number:6,question:"Disease-causing bacteria that are resistant to a particular disease",choices:["should have an adaptive advantage when exposed to this disease.","have a mutation that gives them resistance.","all of the choices","will probably produce offspring that are also disease resistant."],correct:2},{number:7,question:`When scientists refer to "survival of the fittest," fitness refers to a species'`,choices:["strength.","reproductive success.","all of the choices","speed."],correct:1},{number:8,question:"Scientific evidence suggests that the earth's surface has changed significantly over time, as great land masses have moved past and/or into each other. These shifting land masses are connected to subsurface structures called",choices:["tectonic plates.","continents.","fossils.","glaciers."],correct:0},{number:9,question:"Climate changes and asteroids impacting the earth may be seen as opportunities for evolutionary change.",choices:["False","True"],correct:1},{number:10,question:"The process whereby one species changes into one or more other species over time is called",choices:["biodiversity.","genetic diversity.","species richness.","speciation."],correct:3},{number:11,question:"Fortunately for the world, the golden toad, once thought extinct in its Costa Rican rainforests, has been rediscovered.",choices:["True","False"],correct:1},{number:12,question:"If you found 20 different plant species in a 1m2 area, but only one of each species, we would say there was",choices:["low species evenness and high species richness.","high species evenness and low species richness.","high species evenness and high species richness.","low species evenness and low species richness."],correct:0},{number:13,question:"The American alligator, once nearly hunted to extinction, is making a comeback. It plays an essential role in its habitat because its nesting mounds and resting holes are important to the lives of other species. The alligator is also important in keeping some prey populations in check. Should such an important species become extinct, there would be devastating consequences to its ecosystem. Such a species is called a/an ________ species.",choices:["native","keystone","indicator","exotic"],correct:1},{number:14,question:'The role that a species plays in its ecosystem, its "way of life" or pattern of living, is called its',choices:["habitat.","ecosystem.","niche.","species richness."],correct:2},{number:15,question:'Some lichens (an "organism" composed of a fungus and an alga) are particularly sensitive to industrial pollutants, especially factory smoke. Scientists have been able to use lichens as a measure of pollution since greater lichen deaths mean higher pollution amounts. Because we can use lichens in this way, we say they are',choices:["foundation species.","keystone species.","specialist species.","indicator species."],correct:3},{number:17,question:"While some landowners may consider beavers a pest, they are important to their ecosystem: the dams they build create wetland that many other species use. Because of the role they play, we call them ________ species.",choices:["foundation","indicator","endangered","vermin"],correct:0}],t={id:e,displayName:s,questions:i};export{t as default,s as displayName,e as id,i as questions};
